#### suvijain@gmail.com

Rochester, NY Github: simplysuvi

https://simplysuvi.github.io

+1 5857108813

## **Skills**

Java

**Python** 

**JavaScript** 

**HTML** 

**CSS** 

## **Tools**

IntelliJ IDE

JMP (SAS Software)

Pandas library (Python)

NumPy (Python)

Scikit (Python)

WordPress CMS

SalesForce Marketing Cloud

## **SUVRAT JAIN**

# **Graduate student (Data Science)**

## Summary

A competent & committed Master's student with 2 years of experience in the Software industry, looking to further develop my software engineering and data science skills, and gain hands-on experience in the data science and software industry. Currently looking for a suitable graduate co-op or internship opportunity with a progressive employer to get hands-on experience in the data science and software industry and prove to be a reliable asset to the company.

#### **Education**

### M.Sc. (Data Science)

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY, United States Since August 2021

Relevant courses: Applied Statistics, Java and Python for Data Science, Database design and management using MySQL.

## **Bachelor of Technology (Electronics & Communication Engineering)**

Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Dubai, United Arab Emirates From September 2017 to July 2019

## Work experience

#### **Email Developer**

Merkle Inc., Pune, India From September 2020 to August 2021

- Created 100+ email campaigns for Estee Lauder and MAC Cosmetics using Salesforce Marketing Cloud, delivering an average click-through rate of 25%.
- Developed and delivered personalized email campaigns with a reach of more than 400,000 customers in 100+ countries worldwide, using Braze.
- Debugged cross-browser compatibility issues between browsers, verifying 100% compliance with code standards.

#### **QA** Associate (Intern)

Merkle Inc., Pune, India From January 2020 to September 2020

- Reduced overall test cycle time by 40% using Python scripting in automation testing.
- Identified & reported 500+ unique bugs across web & mobile applications for UltraTech Cement, in what was to be one of the most successful launches of the company's digital initiative.
- Performed manual testing of mobile applications, including smoke, functional, integration, regression, user acceptance, and UI testing for multiple releases each sprint.

## Web Developer (Intern)

## Arachnomesh Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Navi Mumbai, India

From July 2018 to September 2018

- Accelerated page load times by ~22% through optimization of CSS, HTML, and JS.
- Designed web application components in Angular JS, including login interface and dashboard views.
- Developed 10+ responsive web pages for clients in a variety of industries, utilizing HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery to design interactive user experience.

# **Projects**

- Predicting Hospital readmission for patients using Machine Learning (Github)
- Hypothesis Testing and Analysis on Titanic dataset (Statistical Testing using JMP)